Guide to the Linda Mary Montano Papers, 1931-2014 MSS.386
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Art Practice, 267147
  - Subseries F: Photos, 267159
    Subseries F contains photographic material of both a personal and professional nature. Other photographic material related to collaborations, teaching, and family can be found within Series II-V.
    - Performance Photos, undated; 270052 (Binder A)
    - Performance Photos, 1974-1976, undated; 270053 (Binder B)
      Binder B includes:
      "A Home Event, Sept. 1974," Sept. 1974-Sept. 1976 "Photo a Day by Linda Montano," [1974] "Mikhail Horowitz Bud Plate Materials," 1983 Untitled Performance Photos
    - Performance Printed Photos from Untitled Binder, undated; 269891 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Personal Photos, undated; 270054 (Binder C)
    - Personal Photos, undated; 270055 (Binder D)
    - Untitled Performance Prints, undated; 269892 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Artworks, 267160
    This series contains some of Montano's artwork, including her series of "Dad Paintings," and her "Shoe" series. It also documents the art she produced and outifits she during her performance "7 Years of Living Art," and her study of the chakras. Other pieces include prints, pencil sketches, paintings, drawings. Montano also kept annotated photo albums and scrapbooks that were created both by her and her grandmother. A large portion of artwork can also be found in Oversize Series I, Subseries G.
    - Birth Drawings, undated; 269893 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Chakra Drawings, 1989-1998, undated; 269894 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - "Chakra Girl", 1998; 269895 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Chicken Drawing on Fabric, undated; 269896 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Dad Paintings [1 of 15], 2002-2004; 269897 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Dad Paintings [2 of 15], 2002-2004; 269898 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Dad Paintings [3 of 15], 2002-2004; 269899 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Dad Paintings [4 of 15], 2002-2004; 269900 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - Dad Paintings [5 of 15], 2002-2004; 269901 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - Dad Paintings [6 of 15], 2002-2004; 269902 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - Dad Paintings [7 of 15], 2002-2004; 269903 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - Dad Paintings [8 of 15], 2002-2004; 269904 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - Dad Paintings [9 of 15], 2002-2004; 269906 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Dad Paintings [10 of 15], 2002-2004; 269907 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Dad Paintings [11 of 15], 2002-2004; 269908 (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Dad Paintings [12 of 15], 2002-2004; 269909 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Dad Paintings [13 of 15], 2002-2004; 269910 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Dad Paintings [14 of 15], 2002-2004; 269911 (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Dad Paintings [15 of 15], 2002-2004; 269912 (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Diagram Drawings, undated; 269955 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Dream Drawings, 1978; 269956 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Dry-erase Notes, undated; 269957 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Edgewood College's Signature, Winter/Spring 1967; 269958 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - "Encounter," "Red Time," "Man + Boy," "watusi," "Dance of Death," Untitled, undated; 269959 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - "I Will Follow My Heart", 1975-1976; 269963 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Linda Montano + Tehching Hsieh: Art Life One Year Performance, undated; 269964 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - "Lying in Ecstasy", undated; 269965 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Maxi-Pad Writing Tablet, undated; 269966 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - "Mitchell Shot in Head Murdered by Cousin", 1977; 269968 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - "1 Minute Sketch", undated; 269970 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Paper Man, undated; 269971 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - Portraits in Pencil, undated; 269972 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - Prints by Linda Montano [1 of 3], undated; 269974 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - Prints by Linda Montano [2 of 3], undated; 269975 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Prints by Linda Montano [3 of 3], undated; 269976 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - "Sanctuary", 1967; 269977 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - Sketchbook/Comic, Spring 1978; 269979 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Sketchbook: "Portraits and Automatic Writings", 1978; 269980 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - "Solution", undated; 277653 (Folder 11)
    - "Some Past Performances by Linda M. Montano", [2007]; 269982 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Strathmore Alexis Drawing Pad, undated; 269983 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - Untitled Pencil Sketches [1 of 2], undated; 269985 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Untitled Pencil Sketches [2 of 2], undated; 269986 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Untitled Piece with Red Plastic, undated; 269987 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - Untitled Works [1 of 5], undated; 269993 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Untitled Works [2 of 5], undated; 269994 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Untitled Works [3 of 5], undated; 269995 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Untitled Works [4 of 5], undated; 269996 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Untitled Works [5 of 5], undated; 269997 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Untitled Works on Cloth, undated; 269998 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "We All Partake of the Bread", undated; 270000 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "blue" year of performance, 277348 (Box 86)
      Includes jumpsuit, karate belt, shoes, and selected other clothing. Additional clothing from this performance can be accessed via the donor, Linda Mary Montano.
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "yellow" and "green" years of performance, 277349 (Box 87)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "white" year of performance, 277350 (Box 88)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "purple" year of performance, 277351 (Box 89)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "red" year of performance, 277352 (Box 90)
      Includes jumpsuit, karate belt, shoes, and selected other clothing. Additional clothing from this performance can be accessed via the donor, Linda Montano.
    - 14 Years of Living Art: outfits worn during "orange" year of performance, 277353 (Box 91)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: 7 Scarves, 7 Jackets, undated (Box 105)
    - 14 Years of Living Art: 7 Baby Suits, undated (Box 106)
    - "Suitcase" Costumes, undated (Box 104)
    - Art and Performance Items, 277354 (Box 93)
    - Performance Props, 278816 (Box 95)
    - Leather Jacket Sculpture, 277355
    - Skeleton Prop, 277357 (Box 92)
      One of 7 used in exhibition for 14 years of living art, shown with chakra jumpsuits and associated outfits. Other 6 are available for exhibtion from donor Linda Mary Montano.
    - Chicken Performance Costume, 277356
    - "Chicken Dance: The Streets of San Francisco", 2011 (Box 107)
      Six out of seven exhibition copies of photographs (1972, printed 2011) from "State of Mind: New California Art Circa 1970" exhibition.
- Series II: Inspirational People and Collaborators, 267148
  This series consists of materials related to important collaborations Montano has fostered throughout her career and lifetime. Key collaborators include Annie Sprinkle, Dr. Mehta, Dr. Mishru, Mitchell Payne, Pauline Oliveros, and Tehching Hsieh. Material in this series reflects Montano's performance art/life process, blending the personal with the professional. It includes correspondence, photographic material, research, notes, collaborative works, and press and promotional material.
  - Annie Sprinkle Aphrodite Awards, [2002], undated; 270003 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Annie Sprinkle Correspondence [1 of 5], 1982-2011; 270005 (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Annie Sprinkle Correspondence [2 of 5], 1982-2011; 270006 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Annie Sprinkle Correspondence [3 of 5], 1982-2011; 270007 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Annie Sprinkle Correspondence [4 of 5], 1982-2011; 270008 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Annie Sprinkle Correspondence [5 of 5], 1982-2011; 270009 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Annie Sprinkle: "Linda Montano A Spiritual Treasure" Piece, undated; 270011 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Annie Sprinkle: Love Art Laboratory 7 Wedding Invitations, 2004-2011; 270012 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Annie Sprinkle Photographic Material, undated; 270042 (Binder E)
  - Annie Sprinkle Photographic Material, undated; 271486 (Binder F)
  - Annie Sprinkle Press: Articles and Promotional Materials, 1989-2011; 270013 (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - Annie Sprinkle Promotional Posters, 1983-2011; 270017 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Annie Sprinkle Publications [1 of 2], 1985-1988, undated; 270018 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Annie Sprinkle Publications [2 of 2], 1989-1999; 270019 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Annie Sprinkle: The World's Three Greatest Pieces of Ass by Dr. J. West, undated; 270020 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Annie Sprinkle Writings and Work, 1990-2002; 270021 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Annie Sprinkle's Ecosexual Pride Flag, March 26, 2011; 270022 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Annie Sprinkle's Resume, Medical Letter, and Will, 1986-1991; 270023 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Annie Sprinkle's Photos of Linda Montano in Cherotic Revolutionary, Gender Affects, and Adam, 1989, 1990, 1993; 270024 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Art/Life Original Limited Edition Monthly (Vol. 21, no. 11), 2001; 270025 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Mehta: 2 Interviews/2 Ayurvedic Doctors by Linda M. Montano, 1991; 270026 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Mehta Correspondence, 1990-2000; 270027 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Mehta: Jyotish Charts, 1994, 1999, undated; 270028 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Dr. Arunadevi A. Mehta Last Rites and Cremation, 2009; 270029 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Dr. Mehta: Linda's Lecture Notes, 1991-1995, undated; 270030 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Dr. Mehta Literature, 1987, undated; 270031 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Dr. Mehta: "OM," "Manual Therapy", undated; 270032 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Mehta Photographic Material, undated; 270043 (Binder F)
  - Dr. Mehta: Sojitra Family Wedding Invitation, 2012; 270033 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Mehta: The Wisdom of Mataji and Bapuji, February 2000; 270034 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Mishru (Ananda Ashram) Correspondence [1 of 2], 1980-1991; 270035 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Dr. Mishru (Ananda Ashram) Correspondence [2 of 2], 1980-1994; 270036 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Mishru Photographic Material, undated; 270044 (Binder F)
  - Dr. Mishru Press, Promotional, General Info, undated; 270037 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Mishru Writings and Notes, 1986-1987, undated; 270038 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Dr. Mishru Yoga Research, Info, undated; 270039 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Mitchell's Death, 1971-1984; 270040 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Mitchell's Death: Condolences, 1977-1979; 270041 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Mitchell Payne Certificate of Marriage Registration, June 10, 1971; 270048 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell Payne Correspondence [1 of 2], 1971-1977; 270056 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Mitchell Payne Correspondence [2 of 2], 1971-1979; 270057 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell Payne Divorce Papers, 1976; 270058 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - "Mitchell Payne Linda Montano Wedding Album and Coloring Book", June 6, 1971; 270059 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell Payne Marriage/Divorce Papers, undated; 270060 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell Payne Academic Papers: Aram Yardumian, 2010; 270061 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell Payne Photographic Material, undated; 270045 (Binder G)
  - Mitchell Payne Publicity, 1980-1983, undated; 270062 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Other Artists: Promotional Materials, 1984-2005, undated; 270063 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Pauline Oliveros Correspondence [1 of 4], 1975-2010; 270064 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Pauline Oliveros Correspondence [2 of 4], 1975-2010; 270065 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Pauline Oliveros Correspondence [3 of 4], 1975-2010; 270066 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Pauline Oliveros Correspondence [4 of 4], 1975-2010; 270067 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Pauline Oliveros: Deep Listening Institute Materials, 2006-2010; 270068 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Pauline Oliveros Foundation, undated; 270069 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Pauline Oliveros Lunar Opera, 2000; 270070 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Pauline Oliveros Music Notebook, undated; 270072 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Pauline Oliveros OF Elephants and Peacocks Opera, 2002; 270073 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Pauline Oliveros Photographic Material, 1979, undated; 270046 (Binder H)
  - Pauline Oliveros Portrait of Linda Montano, 1981-1988, undated; 270074 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Pauline Oliveros Programs, 1977-2010; 270075 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Pauline Oliveros Proverbs, 1976, undated; 270076 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Pauline Oliveros' Work and Press, 1976-2000; 270077 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Tehching Hsieh Correspondence, 1983-1985, undated; 270079 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Tehching Hsieh: High Performance Magazine Vol. 7, no. 3, 1984; 270080 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Tehching Hsieh: New Museum, Marcia Tucker: "Choices: Making an Art of Everyday Life", February 1-March 30, 1986; 270082 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Tehching Hsieh: One Year Performance "Artists Want Work", [1983-1984]; 270083 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Books I-III, [1983-1984]; 270085 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Books IV-VI, [1983-1984]; 270105 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Books VII-X, [1983-1984]; 270106 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Monthly Notes, 1983-1984; 270107 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Press [1 of 2], 1983-1984; 270108 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance Press [2 of 2], 1983-1984; 270109 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance: Statements, Notes, and Life Events, 1983-1985; 270112 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Tehching Hsieh Photographic Material, [1982-1985]; 270047 (Binder H)
    Binder H includes: "One Year Performance, Photo a day every day," July 1983-1984
  - Tehching Hsieh Photographic Material, [1982-1985]; 271487 (Binder I)
    Binder I includes: "One Year Performance, Photo a day every day," July 1983-1984, continuted
  - Tehching Hsieh Photographic Material, [1982-1985]; 271488 (Binder J)
    Binder J includes: "Tehching Hsieh One Year Performance," 1983-1984
  - Tehching Hsieh Press Binder, 1983-1985; 270110 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Tehching Hsieh Promotional Cards and Postcards, 1984, 1985, undated; 270111 (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Series III: Correspondence, 267149
  This series contains primarily Montano's personal correspondence, and is arranged alphabetically by last name, when indicated. It includes Montano's collection of fan and student correspondence. Business correspondence can be found in Series I, Subseries A. Correspondence from collaborators and family can be found in Series II and V.
  - Allyn, Jerri, 2001, undated; 270113 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Laurie, 1983; 270114 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Art/Life, 1999-2002; 270115 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Art Mom, 2008-2012; 270116 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Beuys, Joseph, 1971-1980; 270117 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Bryant, Barry, 1984-1993, undated; 270118 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Coco Go, 2001; 270119 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Cohen, Becky, 1983-1993; 270120 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Corner, Philip, undated; 270121 (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Cottingham, Laura, 1998; 270122 (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Cotton, Paul, 1980-1985; 270123 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Estevez, Nicolas Dumit, 2006, undated; 270124 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Finley, Karen, 1983-2001; 270125 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Goldberg, Roselee, 1998, 2000; 270126 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Hammond, Harmony, 1983, 1984, undated; 270127 (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Hay, Deborah, 1983-1996; 270128 (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Hendricks, Geoffrey, 1997; 270129 (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Hendricks, Jon, 1997-1999; 270130 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Henes, Donna, 1980-1989; 270131 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Hershman, Lynn, 1985, undated; 270132 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Higgins, Dick, 1981, 1982; 270133 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Ingber, Lester and Louise, 1979-1995; 270134 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Knowles, Alison, 1983, undated; 270135 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Kuprow, Allan, 1996, undated; 270136 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Lacy, Suzanne, 1981, undated; 270137 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - Lehmann, Minnette, 1977-1998; 270138 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - LeSueur, Meridel, 1983-1988, undated; 270139 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - Lunch, Lydia, 1986, undated; 270140 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - Margaret, 1982; 270141 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Marioni, Tom, 1980-1999, undated; 270142 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - Masa, 1988, undated; 270143 (Box 43, Folder 34)
  - Miss Vera's Finishing School, 1994; 270144 (Box 43, Folder 35)
  - Moore, Frank, May 22, 1989; 270145 (Box 43, Folder 36)
  - O'Grady, Lorraine, September 18, 1981; 270146 (Box 43, Folder 37)
  - Picard, Lil, May 1986; 270147 (Box 43, Folder 38)
  - Roth, Moira, 1980-1998, undated; 270148 (Box 43, Folder 39)
  - Rothenberg, Diane, 1982-1990; 270149 (Box 43, Folder 40)
  - Rothenberg, Jerome, 1982-1986; 270150 (Box 43, Folder 41)
  - Schneemann, Carolee, 1993-2000; 270151 (Box 43, Folder 42)
  - Sharp, Willoughby, 1985-1997; 270152 (Box 43, Folder 43)
  - Sherman, Stuart, undated; 270153 (Box 43, Folder 44)
  - Shitreen, Frank, 1984, undated; 270154 (Box 43, Folder 45)
  - Smith, Barbara, 1984-2011, undated; 270197 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - STELARC, 1976-1996; 270199 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Vera, Veronica, 1989-1997; 270200 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Martha, 1984-2000; 270201 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Zweig, Ellen, 1978-1984, undated; 270202 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Email Correspondence, undated; 270203 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Fan Correspondence: A, 1985-2001; 270204 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Fan Correspondence: B, 1995-1998, undated; 270205 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Fan Correspondence: C, 1987-2009, undated; 270206 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Fan Correspondence: D, 1982, 1990, undated; 270207 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Fan Correspondence: F, 1982-2011, undated; 270208 (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Fan Correspondence: G, 1992-1999; 270209 (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Fan Correspondence: H, 1982-2001; 270210 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Fan Correspondence: I, 1985-1999; 270211 (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - Fan Correspondence: J, 1994-2006, undated; 270212 (Box 44, Folder 15)
  - Fan Correspondence: K, 1986-2007; 270213 (Box 44, Folder 16)
  - Fan Correspondence: L, 1985-2007; 270214 (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - Fan Correspondence: M, 1982-2011, undated; 270215 (Box 44, Folder 18)
  - Fan Correspondence: N, 1984, 1996; 270216 (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - Fan Correspondence: O, undated; 270217 (Box 44, Folder 20)
  - Fan Correspondence: P, 1984-2004; 270218 (Box 44, Folder 21)
  - Fan Correspondence: Q, 2008, undated; 270219 (Box 44, Folder 22)
  - Fan Correspondence: R, 1975-2012; 270220 (Box 44, Folder 23)
  - Fan Correspondence: S, 1986-2000; 270221 (Box 44, Folder 24)
  - Fan Correspondence: T, 1997-2010; 270222 (Box 44, Folder 25)
  - Fan Correspondence: U, 1998; 270223 (Box 44, Folder 26)
  - Fan Correspondence: V, 2011; 270224 (Box 44, Folder 27)
  - Fan Correspondence: W, 1985-2011, undated; 270225 (Box 44, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified Fan Correspondence: 1980s, 1980-1989; 270226 (Box 44, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified Fan Correspondence: 1990s, 1990-1999; 270227 (Box 44, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified Fan Correspondence: 2000s, 2000-2014; 270228 (Box 44, Folder 31)
  - Unidentified Fan Correspondence: undated [1 of 2], 270237 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Fan Correspondence: undated [2 of 2], 270243 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence [1 of 2], 1970-2000; 270244 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence [2 of 2], 1970-2000; 270245 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Student/Peer Correspondence [1 of 5], 1980-2000; 270246 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Student/Peer Correspondence [2 of 5], 1980-2000; 270247 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Student/Peer Correspondence [3 of 5], 1980-2000; 270248 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Student/Peer Correspondence [4 of 5], 1980-2000; 270249 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Student/Peer Correspondence [5 of 5], 1980-2000; 270250 (Box 45, Folder 9)
- Series IV: Teaching, 267150
  This series contains syllabi, academic papers, correspondence, and quarterly student evaluations from Montano's time as a professor and guest lecturer at several different institutions, including the University of Texas at Austin, UCLA, and San Francisco Art Institute. A bulk of the material also contains Montano's student files, which contain resumes and a collection of theses that discuss, interpret and analyze Montano's work. Also represented in this series is the in-depth documentation of Montano's request for tenure at UT Austin. This material, which includes writing, correspondence, statements, and press, formed the narrative for Montano's performance piece "Tenure."
  - Abrams, Damali, 2007; 270251 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Bonhomme, Carole, undated; 270252 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Burgess, Martha: "Art: Seven Living Years" for Stroll, Spring/Summer 1985; 270253 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Class Descriptions and Notes, 1981-2000; 270254 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Collection of Student Papers from "History of Performance Art" Class, 1996; 270255 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Collection of Student Papers from "History of Performance" Class, 1997; 270256 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Collection of Student Papers from "History of Performance" Class, 1993; 270257 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Collection of Student Papers from "History of Performance Art: Rite of Passage" Class, 1993; 270258 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Cooley, C. Ryder, undated; 270259 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Crawford, Leslie, 2008; 270260 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - DeWalt, Rob: "Twenty-Four Seen, the Art/Life of Linda Montano", February 22-February 28, 2013; 270261 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Dunphy, Didi, 1985; 270262 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Eyler, Carolyn: "Montano's Gift", 1999; 270263 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Fernos, Fausto, 1992; 270264 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Festa, Angelika: "Redemption in the Art and Life Performances of Linda Montano" [1 of 2], 1989; 270265 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Festa, Angelika: "Redemption in the Art and Life Performances of Linda Montano" [2 of 2], 1989; 270266 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Festa, Angelika: "Shall We Talk? Linda Montano Performs Autobiographical Voices", August 1997, February 1998; 270267 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Fisher, Jennifer: "Seven Years of Living Art" in Parachute #64, undated; 270268 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Gamper, Gisela: Fabrications, 1997; 270269 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Generali Foundation: "Double Life", 2001; 270270 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Glick, Elise, 2008; 270271 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Gordon, Lori: "The Story of My Life", April 2004; 270272 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Grenier, Catherine: "Experimental City", undated; 270273 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Grosberg, Kali, 1979, undated; 270274 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Gutelius, Josepha: "The Ballad of Elektra", undated; 270275 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Hannan, Joe: Review in LIVE Performance Art #3, Spring 1980; 270276 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Hewitt, Susan, 1984; 270277 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Hinshaw, Rachel Martin: "Performing Music in Linda Montano's 'Sounding the Chakras'", February 11, 1996; 270278 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Holmes, Tom: Precedent of Cutting in Performance Art, 1997-1998; 270279 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Kereszi, Victoria: "Making a Record...", May 2010; 270280 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Keyes, Roger, 1993; 270281 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Kim, Yeonglan, May 1998; 270282 (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Koplan, Steven: Review for Afterimage, February 1986; 270283 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - LaMont, Justine: "Intersection: Women's Performance Art", April 8, 1996; 270284 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Lindsay, Arturo: "Performance Art Ritual as Postmodern Thought: An Aesthetic Investigation", 1990; 270285 (Box 47, Folder 19)
  - Maclin, Courtney, 1996; 270286 (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Malloy, Patricia: "Evolution of the Environmental: The Realization of Space in 20th Century Art", 1988; 270287 (Box 47, Folder 21)
  - Manning, Toni, 1996; 270288 (Box 47, Folder 22)
  - Martin, Rachel: "Les Tres Riches Heures de Felix et Dangerose", June 19, 2009; 270289 (Box 47, Folder 23)
  - Miller, E. E., 2005; 270290 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Mitchell, Larry, 1994; 270291 (Box 48, Folder 2)